So the dots that were
on that windshield
are formed by air coolant.
That's how tempered
glass is made.
It goes through what's called
a [? lear ?] or a rolling
conveyor, and it's heated
up very, very quickly,
and then it's
cooled very quickly.
And it's cooled by this
array of compressed air jets
on both sides that take it
from almost the transition
temperature--
it just about wants
to move but doesn't
quite, down to room temperature
in three minutes or so.
And that super-rapid cooling
is what generates that stress
on the--
the difference
between the inside
and the outside
temperature in the glass.
And so it's air cooled,
but Prince Rupert
drop is cooled by--
anyone want to guess?
Water.
Yeah, by water.
So water is a better
coolant, right?
So as a result, you
get a lot more stress
embodied with the glass,
a lot more stress.
And so that's
relevant because you
don't want to make a window that
breaks with that kind of energy
and so you get explosive
energy all over the place.
So tempered glass is
engineered to fail.
It's very strong,
but it's engineered
to fail so that when it breaks,
it breaks into small pieces
so that if you're walking along
the sidewalk and a skyscraper
blows out a window, you don't
get huge shards of glass
falling down and hurting people.
You get little pellets
gently raining down,
which isn't such a bad thing.
[LAUGHTER]